EDUCATION:

B. Tech in Computer Science and Engineering from LKCE, Jalandhar affiliated to Punjab Technical University (2015 -2019)

12th Standard from DMS Jalandhar, affiliated to CBSE

10th Standard from DMS

Jalandhar, affiliated to CBSE

PROJECTS:

- <u>SearsHomeServices.com</u>
- Medpiper Landing website. (https://medpiper.com/)
- Savage web app.
- Savage admin panel.
- Stolt-Nielsen landing website.
 (https://www.stolt-nielsen.com/)
- Form builder component.
- Service-now Dashboard (Power BI)

KEY DIFFERENTIATORS:

- Motivator
- Troubleshooter
- Team Player
- Intuitive
- Quick Learner
- Smart Worker

KEY IMPACT AREAS:

- Working with cross-functional teams
- Launching production-ready code
- Changing code as per dynamic requirements of business
- Code reviews
- Performance optimization

PARAS DUA

https://parasdua.netlify.app/ parasdua1997@gmail.com

+91 - 8568015594

EXECUTIVE PROFILE

Performing professional with 5+ years of experience into Front-end development with passion for coding and keeping up with the latest trends in software development and technology. Success in exceeding quality of service commitments and development of required solutions within defined timelines of business services. Skilled in process analysis & improvement, web application development consuming REST services. Developing applications in an agile way to fulfill the deadlines on time.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sears Holdings India as Technical Associate

January 2023 - Current

Responsive Web application development using Next.js.

Mobcoder Technologies Pvt Ltd as SDE 2

December 2021 - December 2022

Web application development using React.js, Next.js and Redux.

Tata Consultancy Services Limited as Systems Engineer

June 2019 - December 2021

Web application development using React.js and Redux.

Services and Operations:

- Requirement analysis, scoping, proof of concept, deployment and operations.
- Working closely with designers and engineers to build a compelling product
- Responsible for seamless UI development of Web Applications using React.js in Agile environment.
- Responsible for bringing in the improvements and new exciting functionalities in existing applications.
- Responsible for unit testing of each component developed using React testing library.

SKILLS

JavaScript React.js
TypeScript Next.js
CSS3 Git
GraphQL HTML5
Redux AWS
Node.js JEST